John E Baltes II

A Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for front end design and technologies. Past experience in GIS mapping and visualization has driven my passion to learn and grow. Known as an ambitious and rapid learner, who has experienced success as a result of commitment to continuous learning.

3168 Indianola Rd Apt C Columbus, OH 43202 (937) 272-0959 baltescartography@gmail.com Retrojb.github.io github.com/Retrojb linkedin.com/in/john-baltes

EXPERIENCE

Nationwide Insurance, Columbus, OH — Associate Applications Developer (October 2018 - Current)

Full Stack Software Engineer. Worked on an internal HR resource management app. Work includes writing Postgres DB queries, backend development with classes, services, controllers. Front end development work included Angular 6, NGrX, building utility services, and data services. Built metrics in Splunk and New Relic. Project methodology was Agile, with a focus on continuous integration and testing pipelines with concourse CI, deploying images to Docker, containers to Kubernetes and deployment to the AWS cloud

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH — Undergraduate Researcher(*September 2016 - June 2017*)

Studied Spatial analysis of pastoralists tribes in Cameroon, Africa. Interpreted, converted and analyzed maps and data for an understanding of ecological effects of pastoralists in a specific region. Invited to join a project on spatial analysis of historical Yemen tribes to study historical movement in the region.

Geopro Consultants LLC, Dayton, OH, — GIS Technician Intern (October 2015 - April 2016)

Data collection and conversion for the City of Dayton Civil Engineering Department to gain a modern inventory of street light locations. Operated Trimble Total Station, GNS Rovers Laser Measurement tools to gain the most accurate geographic location. Analyzed, processed and converted data into usable GIS data points using CAD tools.

Technical Inventory

Java, Angular 7, Ionic 3, Swift5, Kotlin, MongoDb, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Cordova, Postman, Apigee, Spring MVC, OWASP, Node JS, Typescript, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Git, SQL, NoSQL, ORM, Web Authentication,

AWARDS

Published cartographer: At the Wright Dunbar Historical Museum (Dayton, OH)

3rd Place Contestant in AAG East Lake Conference: For the Dayton Walkability index.

EDUCATION

We Can Code IT, Columbus, OH — *Certificate of Software Development*

5-star-rated coding bootcamp, learning agile full-stack software development from expert instructors and intensive hands on projects. Planned, designed, and developed professional applications in collaborative team-based and independent settings, demonstrating the proficiency to earn a Software Development Certificate.

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH — BS, Geographic Informations Systems

Undergraduate degree in GIS using modern mapping techniques to spatially analyze data for clients and research purposes. Ability to build databases, write scripts, and deliver final maps to end users.

PROJECTS

Nationwide Mobile Application—Angular 5, Ionic 3, Cordova 3, Apigee, PCI Compliant, Postman, Typescript.

Poly skilled in development, requirements, metrics and telemetry. Large Enterprise mobile application used to deliver clients with the best mobile insurance experience. Worked in an agile team working on money movement, required PCI compliance and OWASP.

Nationwide Internal Resource Tracker— Java 8, Angular 7, Concourse CI, Maven, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Splunk, Requirements, E2E Testing, Agile

Full Stack development of a Nationwide Internal application. Saw project from planning to production. Gained necessary knowledge to deploy applications to the AWS cloud. Furthered development skills in Java and Angular along with other skills.

MyMenu App — Java, TDD, HTML5, CSS3, Spring MVC, Thymeleaf, H2, Ajax, Javascript, H2 DB

We Can Code IT final project, based on revolutionizing the restaurant experience, by building a full-stack web application that allow clients to view menus from multiple restaurants. Managers had the ability to add, edit, delete items and menus.